HAN KI Stark!
斯塔克
You're supposed to be in Moscow.
你现在应该是在莫斯科的
I took a detour...
我绕了个道
Through your defense lab.
经过了你的防御实验室
Even for this group, that takes nerve.
即使是为了公司 你们也太胆大妄为了
May I remind you, Dr. Pym, that you're a soldier...
需要我提醒你吗 皮姆博士 你是一名军人…
I'm a scientist.
我是科学家
Then act like one.
那就表现得像个科学家
Help us put it to good use.
帮我们好好利用它
I let you turn me into your errand boy,
你把我当成跑腿的也就算了
If only you'd protected Janet with such ferocity, Dr. Pym.
如果你当初这么拼命地保护珍妮特就好了 皮姆博士
--Easy, Hank.
冷静点 汉克
Hank,
我们需要你
We shouldn't let him leave the building.
我们不应该让他离开这座大厦
You've already lied to him. Now you want to go to war with him?
你们已经骗了他 现在还想对他开战吗
Yes.
是的
Our scientists haven't come close to replicating his work.
我们的科研人员根本没法复制他的实验成果
You really want to find out what it's like when you can't see him coming?
你真的想再试试 看不见他是什么情形吗
I've known Hank Pym for a long time.
我认识汉克·皮姆很久了
He's no security risk.
他不是危险分子
You like that?
喜欢吗
Come get you some now.
喜欢就来尝尝
You didn't even move.
你怎么没有反应
Nah.
没反应
What if I come in on the left side, right? Just down here.
如果我从左边开打呢 下面这里
You see this right here?
你看见这里了吗
I'm gonna miss you, Scott.
我会想你的 斯科特
I'm gonna miss you, too, Peachy.
我也会想你的 皮奇
Man, you guys got the weirdest goodbye rituals.
伙计 你们的欢送仪式太奇怪了
All right, break it up.
好啦 散啦
Break it up! Break it up!
散啦 散啦
Scotty!
斯科特
What's up, man!
怎么了 兄弟
Damn! Hey.
我靠 嘿
Ha-ha! Hey, man.
哈哈 嘿 兄弟
Hey, what's up with your eye?
你眼睛怎么了
Oh. Well, what do you think? Peachy. It's a going-away present.
还能怎么样 皮奇干的 算是告别礼物
Oh, yeah. I still got my scar from a year ago.
对哦 我一年前留下的伤疤还在呢
- Oh, yeah. -Yeah.
哦 是啊
You know what? I'm still the only one who knocked him out.
你知道吗 我依旧是唯一将他击倒的人
Well, I definitely didn't.
好吧 我肯定不行
Thanks for picking me up, brother.
谢谢你来接我 兄弟
Bro, you think I'm gonna miss my celly getting out?
兄弟 你觉得我会错过狱友出狱吗
Hey, how's your girl, man?
嘿 你女朋友怎么样了 兄弟
Oh, she left me.
她把我给甩了
And my dad got deported.
我爸爸也被驱逐出境了
But I got the van!
不过我还有这辆面包车
- It's nice. -Yeah, right?
挺不错的
Thanks for the hook-up, too. I needed a place to stay.
谢谢你让我借住 我正需要有个地方住呢
You wait till you see this couch. You're gonna be really happy.
等到你看见那张沙发再谢我吧 你会非常喜欢的
You're gonna be on your feet in no time. Watch.
躺下就不想起来了 看着吧
- I hope so. -Yeah.
-希望如此 -是啊
And I gotta introduce you to some people. Some really skilled people.
我还会介绍几个人给你
- Not interested. - Yeah, right.
-没兴趣 -好吧
No, I'm serious, man. I'm not going back.
不 我是认真的 兄弟 我可不想再回头了
I got a daughter to take care of.
我有个女儿要照顾
You know that jobs don't come easy for ex-cons, right?
你知道犯有前科的人找工作可不容易 对吧
Look, man, I got a master's in electrical engineering, all right?
听着 兄弟 我有电气工程硕士学位
I'm gonna be fine.
我会没事的
Welcome to Baskin-Robbins.
欢迎光临芭斯罗缤
Would you like to try our Mango Fruit Blast?
你想试试我们的芒果冰沙吗
Uh, no, thanks.
不用了 谢谢
Um, I will have... I'll have a burger, please.
呃 我要一个… 我要一个汉堡 谢谢
Oh, we don't... We don't make that.
我们没有… 我们不卖这个
It's ice cream. Baskin-Robbins.
这里是卖冰激凌的 芭斯罗缤
I'll just do, like, whatever's hot and fresh.
那就 随便来点新鲜出炉的
Can I see you in the back, chief? Pronto.
到我办公室来一下 马上
Sure thing, Dale.
没问题 戴尔
Darby, could you just, uh, take care of this idiot? Thanks.
戴比 能过来接待一下这个白痴吗 谢谢
- Hey, Dale. -Come on in.
嘿 戴尔
Pull up some chair.
找把椅子坐
Three years at San Quentin, huh?
在圣昆廷坐了三年牢 对吗
You found out.
你查到了
Baskin-Robbins always finds out.
芭斯罗缤总会查到的
Look, I'm sorry, all right? But I...
听着 我很抱歉 但我…
No one would hire me.
没人愿意雇我
Breaking and entering. Grand larceny.
非法闯入 重大盗窃案
Look, I'm sorry.
听着 我很抱歉
I don't do it anymore. I just...
-我不会再干了 我只是… -向你致意
- Really? -Yeah.
-真的吗 -真的
Thank you. Thank you.
谢谢 谢谢你
You really stuck it to those billionaire SOBs.
你肯定教训了那些狗娘养的亿万富翁
The more I read about what you did and stuff...
我越了解你都做过了些什么…
I'm like, "Wow, I know this guy?
我就越会想我居然认识这家伙
"I'm in charge of this guy?"
我竟然是这家伙的上司
Well, I'm very happy in this job,
我做这份工作很开心
and I really just appreciate the opportunity to...
我很珍惜这个机会…
Well, you're fired, of course.
当然了 你被开除了
I can't really keep you on.
我实在无法留你
Wait, what? Fired?
等等 什么 开除
Yeah.
是的
No, it wasn't a violent crime. it was a cool crime.
不 那当然不是暴力犯罪 那是超酷的犯罪
I'll tell you what, though.
但我要告诉你
This will be totally off the books, off the records,
这些将不会被记录在案底
but if you want to grab one of those Mango Fruit Blasts
等一下你卷铺盖走人的时候
on your way out the door,
如果想顺走一个芒果冰沙
I'll just pretend I didn't see it.
我会假装没看见的
Hey, Scotty. What's up?
嘿 斯科特 你好啊
I thought you were supposed to be at work.
我还以为你在上班的
I was. I got fired.
上了 但我被开除了
Damn. They find out who you are?
该死 他们查到你是谁了吗
Yeah.
是的
Baskin-Robbins always finds out, bro.
芭斯罗缤总会查到的 兄弟
Baskin-Robbins don't play.
芭斯罗缤可不是闹着玩的
- You want some waffles? -Yeah, I'll take a waffle.
你要来点华夫饼吗
Oh. That's Kurt.
那是库尔特
He was Folsom for five years. He's a wizard on that laptop.
他在福尔瑟姆监狱待了五年 他可是个电脑奇才
- Nice meet you. -Yeah. Nice to meet you, too.
很高兴认识你
Who are you?
你是谁
Dave.
戴夫
Nice work on the Vista job.
维斯塔公司那一票干得漂亮
Vista job, yes.
维斯塔那票 对
No, no. I have heard of this robbery.
我听说过那起抢劫
Well, technically, I didn't rob them. Robbery involves threat.
严格来说 我没有抢劫 抢劫涉及威胁
I hate violence. I burgled them. I'm a cat burglar.
我讨厌暴力 我那叫入室盗窃 我只是个飞贼
You mean you're a pussy.
你意思是 你是个娘们
Yeah.
好吧
They were overcharging the customers, right?
维斯塔公司高价宰客 对吧
And it added up to millions.
加起来有几百万了
He blows the whistle and he gets fired.
他揭发后却被开除了
And what does he do?
然后你猜他怎么着
He hacks into the security system
他黑进了公司的安全系统
and transfers millions back to the people that they stole it from.
把那几百万转账还给了那些被坑的客户
- Posts all the bank records online.
还把所有的银行交易记录发布到了网上
And he drove the dude's Bentley into his swimming pool.
然后他开着那家伙的宾利冲进了他的游泳池里
What are you doing?
你这是在干嘛
Why are you telling my life story to these guys?
为什么把我的事告诉这些人
What do you want?
你想干什么
My cousin talked to this guy two weeks ago
我表哥两周前跟这家伙谈过
-about this little perfect job. -No way.
是个超级棒的小活
No, no, no. Wait! This guy... This guy fits your M.O.
不不不 等等 那家伙… 那家伙完全对你的口味
No!
不行
I'm finished, man. I'm not going back to jail.
我金盆洗手了 兄弟 我不想再回监狱里去了
It's some retired millionaire living off his golden parachute.
是个靠退休金生活的百万富翁
It's a perfect Scott Lang mark!
这可是斯科特·朗的完美目标
I don't care. I'm out.
我不在乎 我不干
Dr. Pym?
皮姆博士
Yes. I'm still alive.
是的 我还活着
ID?
身份卡
Perhaps that will suffice.
那个应该就能证明了
Very sorry, sir. Please come in.
非常抱歉 先生 请进
Is that Hank Pym?
那是汉克·皮姆吗
Good morning, Hank.
早上好 汉克
Hope.
霍普
Would it kill you to call me Dad?
叫我一声爸爸会死吗
Dr. Cross will be so pleased that you could find the time to join us today.
克罗斯博士肯定非常高兴
More like "thrilled."
更确切的说是欣喜若狂
I was surprised to receive any kind of invitation from you, Darren.
我很意外能收到你发来的邀请信 达伦
What's the occasion?
今天是什么日子
Oh, you'll see. Won't he, Hope?
一会你就知道 对吗 霍普
We're ready for you inside.
我们在里面已经为你准备好了
Ouch.
哎呦
I guess some old wounds never heal, huh?
我猜有些旧伤口愈合不了 对吗
Don't worry, she's in good hands.
别担心 她会得到很好的照顾
You're in for a treat.
你会喜欢的
Long time, no see, Dr. Pym. How's retirement?
好久不见 皮姆博士 退休生活还好吗
How's your face?
你的脸还好吗
After you.
你先请
Now, before we start, I'd like to introduce a very special guest.
在我们开始之前 我想先介绍一位特殊来宾
This company's founder and my mentor,
本公司的创始人 也是我的导师
Dr. Hank Pym.
汉克·皮姆博士
When I took over this company for Dr. Pym,
当我从皮姆博士那里接手这家公司后
I immediately started researching a particle
我立即开始研究一种
that could change the distance between atoms,
能够改变原子间距离
while increasing density and strength.
同时能增加密度和强度的粒子
Why this revolutionary idea remained buried
为什么这个革命性创意一直被
beneath the dust and cobwebs of Hank's research, I couldn't tell you.
汉克雪藏在灰尘和蛛网之下
Butjust imagine,
不过设想一下
a soldier the size of an insect.
一个昆虫般大小的战士
The ultimate secret weapon.
一件终极秘密武器
An Ant-Man.
一个蚁人
That's what they called you. Right, Hank?
他们以前就这么称呼你的 对吧 汉克
Silly, I know.
很傻的名字 我知道
Propaganda.
宣传需要罢了
Tales to astonish!
类似惊奇故事
Trumped-up BS to scare the USSR.
胡编乱造用来吓唬苏联人
Hank, will you tell our guests what you told me
汉克 你可否告诉客人们
every single time I asked you,
每次我问你真的有蚁人吗时
"Was the Ant-Man real?"
你是如何回答的
Just a tall tale.
只是个传说罢了
Right.
没错
Because how could anything so miraculous possibly be real?
因为这么神奇的东西怎么可能会是真的呢
Well, I was inspired by the legend of the Ant-Man.
但我被蚁人的传说激发了灵感
And with my breakthrough shrinking inorganic material,
随着我在非有机材料缩小技术上有所突破
I thought, could it be possible to shrink a person?
我就在想 缩小人类是否可行
Could that be done?
究竟能不能做到
Well, it's not a legend anymore.
其实那已不再是传说
I am proud to present the end of warfare as we know it.
我骄傲的向你们展示当代战争的终结者
The Yellowjacket!
黄蜂战衣
Oh, no.
哦 不
The Yellowjacket is an all-purpose weapon of war
黄蜂战衣是一种全能的战争武器
capable of altering the size of the wearer
可以改变穿戴者的大小
for the ultimate combat advantage.
以获得终极的战斗优势
MAN". We live in an era
我们生活在
in which the weapons we use to protect ourselves
一个用武器自卫却不断受到
are undermined by constant surveillance.
实时监控破坏的时代
It's time to return to a simpler age.
是时候回归更简单的时代了
One where the powers of freedom can once again operate openly
一个可以用自由力量光明正大
to protect their interests.
保护自身权益的时代
An all-purpose peace-keeping vessel,
作为一件全能型和平卫士的可穿戴物
the Yellowjacket can manage any conflict
黄蜂战衣可以应付
on the geopolitical landscape
地缘政治环境中的任何冲突
completely unseen.
而不被发现
Efficient in both preventative measures and tactical assault.
高效执行预防性举措和战术性进攻
Practical applications include surveillance,
实用范围包括监视
- industrial sabotage,
工业破坏
and the elimination of obstructions on the road to peace.
以及铲除通往和平途中的所有障碍
A single Yellowjacket
一件黄蜂战衣
offers the user unlimited influence to carry out protective actions.
使用者就可以拥有无限潜能
And, one day soon, an army of Yellowjackets
不久的将来 一个黄蜂战衣的军队
will create a sustainable environment of well-being around the world.
将会在全世界创造出一个
The Yellowjacket.
黄蜂战衣
So, it's a suit?
所以 只是件衣服
Don't be crude, Frank.
别那么轻率 弗兰克
It's not a suit, it's a vessel.
这可不是普通的衣服 而是载体
What's the matter? You're not impressed?
怎么了 没能打动你吗
No, I'm impressed. I'm also concerned.
不 不只打动了我 还把我吓到了
Imagine what our enemies could do with this tech.
想象一下 如果我们的敌人掌握了这种技术会干出什么
We should have a longer conversation about that, Frank.
这个问题我们回头再详细谈 弗兰克
I really value your opinion.
我真的很重视你的意见
Thank you for coming. Hope?
谢谢各位的到来 霍普
Thank you very much, everybody. I will escort you out now.
非常感谢大家 我送你们出去
Thank you.
谢谢
You seem a bit shocked.
你看起来有点震惊
Darren, there's a reason that I buried these secrets.
达伦 我当初把这秘密埋藏起来是有原因的
So you finally admit it!
所以你终于承认了
We could have done this together, Hank. But you ruined that.
我们本来可以合作的 汉克 可你把那机会毁掉了
Don't do this.
停手吧
Dr. Cross?
克罗斯博士
You sell to me first, 20% over your asking price,
你先卖给我 价钱可以再多给你百分之二十
I can have the cash here in two weeks.
两周之内你就可以拿到现金
Deal.
成交
We have to make our move, Hank.
我们得采取行动了 汉克
How close is he?
他进展到哪一步了
He still can't shrink a live subject.
他仍然不能缩小活物
Just give me the suit and let me finish this once and for all.
把套战服给我 让我彻底了结这事
No.
不行
I have Cross' complete trust.
克罗斯现在完全信任我
- It's too dangerous. -We don't have a choice.
太危险了
Well, that's not entirely true.
话可别说得那么绝对
I think I found a guy.
我想我有人选了
Who?
谁
Daddy!
爸爸
Peanut! Oh!
小花生 哦
Happy birthday!
生日快乐
I'm so sorry I'm late.
真抱歉我来晚了
I didn't know what time your party started.
我不知道聚会几点开始
It was on the invitation.
请柬上有写啊
He didn't get an invitation.
没给他发请柬
But he came anyway!
但他还是来了
Well, I'm not gonna miss my little girl's birthday party.
我可不想错过我宝贝女儿的生日派对
I'm gonna go tell Mommy you're here.
我去告诉妈妈你来了
Oh, you don't...
你别…
What are you doing here, Lang?
你来这里干嘛 朗
You haven't paid a dime of child support.
孩子的抚养费你一毛钱都没给过
You know, right now, if I wanted to, I could arrest you.
你知道吗 如果我愿意 现在就可以逮捕你
It's good to see you too, Paxton.
很高兴见到你 帕克斯顿
Mommy's so happy you're here, she choked on her drink.
妈妈听说你来了 高兴得喝水都呛着了
Hey, look what I have for you.
看看我给你带了什么
Can I open it now?
我现在能打开吗
Of course, sweetheart. It's your birthday.
当然了 小宝贝 今天是你生日
You're my bestest friend.
你是我最最好的朋友
What is that thing?
这什么玩意
He's so ugly!
他好丑
I love him!
我爱死他了
Can I go show my friends?
我能拿去给小伙伴们看吗
Of course, sweetheart. Go ahead.
当然 宝贝儿 去吧
You're my bestest friend.
你是我最最好的朋友
Look, the child support is coming, all right?
听着 孩子的抚养费我会给你的 好吗
It's just hard finding a job when you have a record.
只是有前科的人找工作不容易
I'm sure you'll figure it out. But for now, I want you out of my house.
我相信你会有办法的 但是现在 我要你离开我家
- No way! It's my daughter's birthday. -it's my house!
-不可能 今天是我女儿生日 -这是我家
- So what? It's my kid! - Scott!
-那又怎样 她是我的孩子 -斯科特
You can't just show up here. You know that. Come on.
你不能想来就来 你知道的 走吧
It's a birthday party.
可这是生日聚会
Yeah, I know, but you can't just show up.
是 我知道 那你也不能想来就来
She's my daughter.
她是我女儿
You don't know the first thing about being a father.
你根本不知道如何做父亲
Maggie, I tell you this as a friend, and as the first love of my life.
玛姬 我以朋友的身份
Your fiancé is an asshat.
你未婚夫是个傻帽
He's not an asshat.
他不是傻帽
- Hey, watch your language. Okay? -What language? I said "hat."
嘿 说话注意点 行吗
Stop it.
住嘴
Really, Maggie? That guy?
你是认真的吗 玛姬 就那家伙
Come on! You could marry anyone you want,
拜托 你嫁给谁不行
and you have to get engaged to a cop?
偏偏要嫁给警察
At least he's not a crook.
至少他不是罪犯
I'm trying, okay? I've changed. I'm straight.
我在努力 好吗 我改了 改邪归正了
I had a job and...
我有过工作而且…
I wanna provide.
我想要抚养女儿
I had a lot of time to think about it and I love her.
我花了很多时间考虑过 并且我爱她
So much.
非常爱
I've missed so much time and I wanna be a part of her life.
我错过了太多时间 我想成为她生活的一部分
What do I do?
我该怎么做
Get an apartment,
租个房子
get a job, pay child support.
找个工作 付抚养费
And then we will talk about visitation, I promise.
那时我们再来谈探视权 我保证
You're her hero, Scott.
你是她的英雄 斯科特
Just be the person that she already thinks you are.
好好保持你在她心目中的形象
I'm sorry you have such deep concerns about the Yellowjacket, Frank.
我很抱歉让你对黄蜂战衣担忧了 弗兰克
Yeah. Well, uh...
是啊…
Unfortunately, we can't just do whatever we want.
可惜 我们都不能为所欲为
It'd be nice though, right?
那倒是好 对吧
But there are laws.
但还是要遵从法律
What laws? Of man?
什么法律 人类的
The laws of nature transcend the laws of man.
自然的法则高于人类的法律
And I've transcended the laws of nature.
而我已经超越了自然的法则
Darren, I don't think you understand...
达伦 看来你没明白…
Hmm.
嗯
We still haven't worked out all the bugs.
看来我们的技术仍有漏洞
Goodbye, Frank.
再见了 弗兰克
Thank you.
谢谢
You know, I've been thinking a lot about gratitude lately.
你知道吗 我最近经常思考感恩的含义
And today, during my morning meditation,
今天我晨间冥想时
an interesting thought occurred to me, and I think it might apply to you, too.
产生了个有趣的想法
How's that?
此话怎讲
Gratitude can be forgiveness.
感恩可以是宽恕
I've spent years carrying around my anger for Hank Pym.
这么多年来我一直在生汉克·皮姆的气
I devoted my genius to him.
我把自己的才华都贡献给了他
I could have worked anywhere.
本来我去哪工作都可以
I chose my mentor poorly.
我偏偏没选好导师
You didn't even have a choice.
而你却连选择都没有
He never believed in you.
他从不信任你
It's a shame what we had to do, but he forced us to do it, didn't he?
虽然我为咱们所做的事感到惭愧
But we shouldn't be angry, we should be grateful.
但我们不应该愤怒 而是应该感恩
Because his failures as a mentor,
因为他是一个失败的导师
as a father,
一个失败的父亲
forced us to spread our wings.
是他逼得我们展翅高飞
You're a success, Darren.
你是成功的 达伦
You deserve everything coming your way.
将来的一切都是你应得的
Ooh.
哦
Stop cheating.
别耍赖
Hey, what's up, hotshot?
嘿 回来了 高手
Maybe he didn't hear you.
他可能没听见
How was the party?
聚会还好吗
- Tell me about that tip. -What?
跟我说说那一票应该怎么干
I wanna know about that tip.
我想知道那一票应该怎么干
Oh, baby, it's on! It's so on, right now.
噢 宝贝儿 开工了 立刻开工
Calm down, all right? I just need to know where it came from.
先别激动 好吗 我需要知道这票到底是什么来头
It's gotta be airtight.
必须做得天衣无缝
Okay.
好吧
I was at a wine tasting with my cousin Ernesto.
我在一个品酒会上遇到了我表哥埃内斯托
Which was mainly reds, and you know I don't like reds, man.
主要是红酒 你知道我不太喜欢喝红酒的 哥们
But there was a rose that saved the day. it was delightful.
但那天有一种桃红酒 非常好喝
And then he tells me about this girl, Emily, that we used to kick it with.
然后他跟我提到了一个女孩
It was actually the first pair of boobs I ever touched.
其实我第一次摸到的胸部就是她的
It's the wrong details.
我不想听这些细节
It has nothing to do with the story.
这些都跟主题无关
Go.
继续说
So, uh, he tells me that she's working as a housekeeper now, right?
他跟我说 那个叫艾米丽的
And she's dating this dude, Carlos, who's a shot caller from across the bay.
然后她跟一个叫卡洛斯的搞对象
Right? That he's like this big-shot CEO
对吧 那雇主好像是一个大公司的总裁
that is all retired now, but he's loaded.
现在退休了 但有的是钱
And so, Carlos and Ernesto are on the same softball team,
然后 卡洛斯和埃内斯托是同一个垒球队的
and they get to talking, right?
于是他们聊开了 懂吗
And here comes the good part. Carlos says, "Yo, man.
接下来就是重头戏了 卡洛斯说 嘿 伙计
"This guy's got a big-ass safe just sitting in the basement, just chilling."
那家伙有个体积巨大的保险箱
Of course Ernesto comes to me because he knows I got mad thieving skills.
毫无疑问埃内斯托把这件事告诉了我
Of course, I ask him...
然后 我问他
"Did Emily tell Carlos to tell you to get to me what kind of safe it was?"
艾米丽有没有通过卡洛斯告诉你
And he says, "Nah, dawg.
然后他说 没有 老兄
"and whatever's in it, it's gotta be good."
不管里面是什么 肯定很值钱
What?
什么
Old man have safe.
老头子有个保险箱
All right. There's an old man, he's got a safe,
明白了 一个老头 他有个保险箱
Let's just work with that.
来吧 干他一票
You know what I'm saying?
我就是这个意思
Landline's cut, cell signal's jammed.
座机信号切断了 手机信号也瘫痪了
No one will be making for distress call tonight.
今晚没人能报警了
Comm check.
通讯检查
- Check.
-检查 -检查
Hey, if the job goes bad, you know I got your back, right?
如果你失手了 别忘了你还有我这个后援
Don't worry.
不用担心
It's not gonna happen.
不会有这种事的
I love it when he gets cocky.
我就是喜欢他自信满满的样子
Alarm is dead.
报警系统给废了
Nice.
干得漂亮
All right, I'm moving through the house.
好了 我正在穿过房间
There's a fingerprint lock on the door.
门上有个指纹锁
It's got what? Ernesto didn't tell me nothing about that.
有个什么 埃内斯托可没告诉我这些
Aw, man, are we screwed?
兄弟 我们没戏了吗
Not necessarily.
那可不一定
I'm in.
我进来了
No alarms have been triggered. He's in like the Flynn.
没有触发警报 对他而言简直是小菜一碟
Oh, man.
哦 天呐
What is it?
怎么了
Well, they weren't kidding. This safe is serious.
看来他们没骗我们 这保险箱真是固若金汤
How serious are we talking, Scotty?
有多坚固 斯科特
It's a Carbondale.
产自卡本代尔
It's from 1910.
1910年生产的
Made from the same steel as the Titanic.
和泰坦尼克号用的同样的材料
Wow.
哇哦
Can you crack it?
你能打开它吗
Well, here's the thing. it doesn't do so well in the cold.
是这样的 这玩意耐寒性不怎么样
Remember what that iceberg did?
还记得撞冰山的事情吗
Yeah, man. It killed DiCaprio.
当然了 伙计 把小李子给淹死了
Killed everybody.
淹死了所有人
Did not kill the Old lady.
没有淹死那个老太太
She still throw the jewel into the oceans.
她最后还把宝石扔到海里了
What are you doing?
你做了什么
I poured water in the locking mechanism and froze it with nitrogen.
我往锁芯里注水 然后用液氮冷冻
Ice expands. Metal doesn't.
冰会膨胀 金属可不会
- What are you doing now? - Waiting.
-那你现在在干嘛 -在等
Waiting.
在等
Nice.
不错
What is it? Cash? Jewels?
里面有什么 钞票 珠宝
- There's nothing here. -What did you say?
-里面什么都没有 -你说什么
- It's a suit. -What?
只有一套衣服
It's an old motorcycle suit.
是一套旧的机车服
There's no cash, no jewelry, nothing?
没有钞票 没有珠宝 什么都没有吗
No.
没有
It's a bust.
我们扑了个空
I'm really sorry, Scotty.
真是对不住 斯科特
I know you needed to score.
我明白你想要捞一票
I thought we were using mice.
我以为我们要用老鼠
What's the difference?
有什么区别吗
Commence Experiment 34-C. Organic atomic reduction.
准备34-C号实验 缩小有机原子
--Darren, maybe we should think...
达伦 也许我们该再考虑一下
Shrinking organic tissue is the centerpiece of this technology.
缩小有机组织是这项技术的核心
I can't go to the buyers with half a breakthrough.
我可不能把半成品交给买家
Experiment 34-C results,
34-C号试验
negafive.
失败
Sanitize the work station. Bring in subject 35-C.
给实验台消毒 把35-C号实验对象带来
Why would you lock this up?
为什么你会把这个锁起来
This is so weird.
真是奇怪
Scotty, what's up, man?
怎么了 斯科特
I wonder... What is this?
我想知道 这是什么
The world sure seems different from down here, doesn't it, Scott?
从这个角度看世界
What? Who said that?
什么 谁在说话
Luis, down here!
路易斯 我在下面
It's a trial by fire, Scott. Or, in this case,
这是一次艰难的考验 斯科特 或者说
water.
是来自水的考验
Guess you're tougher than you thought.
看来你比想象中的要厉害
Oh, I don't want to see this!
我可不想看你脱衣服
Luis!
路易斯
Son of a...
混蛋
What the hell?
搞什么鬼
HANK". Not bad for a test drive.
初次试验还不错
Keep the suit. I'll be in touch.
保管好衣服 我还会和你联系的
No! No! No, thank you!
不 不 不 不用了
You are under arrest!
你被捕了
No, I didn't steal anything! I was returning something I stole.
我没有偷东西 我是来还我偷的东西
Oh...
哦
Don't move.
不许动
You know, you almost had us convinced
你知道吗 我们差点都相信
that you were gonna change your ways.
你改过自新了
They were really rooting for you.
母女俩都很看好你
It's gonna break their hearts.
这会伤了她们的心的
- You got a visitor. -Who?
有人来探视你了
Your lawyer.
你的律师
MY l8Wyer?
我的律师
I told you I'd be in touch, Scott.
我说过我还会跟你联系的 斯科特
I'm starting to think that you prefer the inside of a jail cell.
我在想你是不是比较喜欢蹲局子
Oh, man.
天呐
Sit down.
坐吧
Sir, I'm sorry I stole the suit.
先生 我很抱歉我偷了你的衣服
I don't even wanna know why you have it.
我甚至不知道为什么你会拥有那件衣服
Maggie was right about you.
玛姬没看错你
How do you know about...
你怎么知道玛姬
No wonder she's trying to keep you away from Cassie.
难怪她不让你接近凯茜
The moment things get hard,
每当事情得不到很好的解决
you turn right back to crime.
你就会走老路去犯罪
The way I see it, you have a choice.
不过要我说 你还是有选择的余地的
You can either spend the rest of your life in prison,
要么你选择在监狱里度过余生
or go back to your cell
要么你先回拘留室
and await further instructions.
等我下一步的指令
I don't understand.
我没搞明白
No, I don't expect you to.
我也没指望你明白
But you don't have many options right now, and quite frankly,
不过你现在没别的选择了 而且老实说
neither do I.
我也一样
Why do you think I let you steal that suit in the first place?
难道你没想过 一开始就是我布局让你偷战服的吗
What?
什么
Second chances don't come around all that much.
这样的机会可不是经常都有的
So, next time you think you might see one,
所以 如果你遇到了这样的机会
I suggest you take a real close look at it.
我建议你最好认真仔细的考虑一下
You're my bestest friend!
你是我最好的朋友
Are you sure you don't want a different toy?
你真的不要换一个玩具吗
No, I love this one.
不 我就喜欢这个
Okay. Well, get some sleep. I love you.
好吧 快睡吧 我爱你
- M0mmy? "Hmm?
-妈妈 -怎么了
Is Daddy a bad man?
爸爸真的是坏人吗
I heard some grownups say he's bad.
我听一些大人说他很坏
No.
不是的
Daddy just gets confused sometimes, you know?
爸爸只是有时候犯糊涂 你明白吗
Smart choice. You actually listened, for once.
明智的选择 你终于开窍了
Under the door.
从门下面走
Okay, where to now?
好了 现在去哪
HANK". Hang tight. -Oh, God.
-稍等 -哦 天呐
What, what?
什么 你说什么
Where the hell did he go?
他到底跑哪去了
I have no idea. He just vanished.
我不知道 他就这么凭空消失了
Set up a five-block perimeter. Now!
立刻封锁附近五个街区 马上
Get back! Get back!
退后 退后
HANK". Scott, these are my associates.
斯科特 这些是我的伙伴
Is that a camera on an ant?
蚂蚁身上装了摄像头吗
Yeah, sure. Why not?
是啊 不然呢
Where's the car?
车在哪里
No car. We've got wings.
没有车 我们用翅膀
Incoming!
来了
Put your foot on the central node and mount the thorax.
脚踩在中间那节 然后骑到它胸部
- How safe is... - Just get on the damn ant, Scott!
-这玩意安全 -赶紧骑上去 斯科特
Why am I on a police car? Shouldn't I not be on a police car?
我怎么在警车上
So they can give you a lift past their five-block perimeter.
这样你们就能搭顺风车
All right.
好吧
- Now, what's the next move? - Hang on tight.
-接下来怎么做 -抓牢
Oh, this is easy! I'm getting the hang of this.
这挺简单的嘛 我已经能控制它了
Yank up to go up. It's like a horse.
想往上飞就往上拉 就像骑马一样
You're throwing 247 off balance.
你让247快要失去平衡了
Wait, his name is 247?
等等 他叫247
He doesn't have a name, he has a number, Scott.
他没有名字 只有编号 斯科特
Do you have any idea how many ants there are?
你知道一共有多少蚂蚁吗
Whoa!
哦
Maybe it's... Maybe it's 248.
也有可能它是 可能它是248
No, no! Vertigo, vertigo!
别 别 好晕 好晕
- No, I think it's 247. - Wait.
不 我认为它就是247
Hang on tight!
抓紧点
I think I'm getting the hang of this.
我想我找到控制它的窍门了
I am controlling 247. He is not listening to you.
是我在控制247 它不听你的
What?
什么
- Can I make one little request? -No.
-我能提一点小小的要求吗 -不能
Stop, 247! Time out, time out.
停下 247 先停一下 先停一下
Time out.
停一下
All right, hold on.
好了 抓紧了
Just wait! Whoa!
等一下 哦
What happens if I throw up in this helmet?
如果我吐在头盔里怎么办
It's my helmet, Scott. You do not throw up.
那是我的头盔 斯科特 你不准吐
Let's set her down, all right?
让她把我放下来 行吗
I'm getting light-headed.
我已经开始头晕了
Hang on, Scott.
坚持住 斯科特
I'm getting a little light...
我真的有点晕了
I need a snooze button.
我得小睡一会
Hit me in 5 minutes.
五分钟后叫我
Hello.
你好
Who are you?
你是谁
Have you been standing there, watching me sleep, this whole time?
你一直站在这里 看着我睡觉吗
Yes.
没错
Because the last time you were here, you stole something.
因为你上次来的时候 偷走了一件东西
Oh. Oh.
哦 哦
Hey, look...
听我说
Whoa!
哦
Paraponera clavata.
学名 帕拉珀尼拉克拉瓦塔
Giant tropical bullet ants,
是一种长得像子弹的巨型热带蚂蚁
ranked highest on the Schmidt pain index.
在施密特刺痛指数中位列第一
They're here to keep an eye on you when I can't.
我不在的时候它们会在这看着你
Dr. Pym's waiting for you downstairs.
皮姆博士在楼下等你
Who?
谁
Hey!
嘿
Um... Whose pajamas are these?
呃… 这是谁的睡裤
How am I supposed to do this?
这要怎么过去
All right, just one step at a time.
好吧 一步一步慢慢走
You don't bite me, I don't step on you. Deal?
你们不咬我 我就不踩你们 好吧
I could take down the servers and Cross wouldn't even know it.
我可以拆除服务器
We don't need this guy.
我们不需要这家伙
I assume that you've already met my daughter, Hope.
我想你已经见过我女儿霍普了
I did. She's great.
是的 她人很好
She doesn't think that we need you.
她觉得我们不需要你
We don't. We can do this ourselves.
不需要 我们可以自己解决
I go to all this effort to let you steal my suit,
我费尽心思让你来偷我的战衣
and then Hope has you arrested.
然后霍普再让你被捕
Okay, we can try this and when he fails, I'll do it myself.
好吧 我们可以让他试试 如果失败了 我就亲自出马
She's a little bit anxious.
她有点焦虑
It has to do with this job,
和这次任务有关
which, judging by the fact that you're sitting opposite me,
鉴于你已经坐在我对面了
I take it that you're interested in.
我猜你会对它感兴趣的
What job?
什么任务
Would you like some tea?
想来点茶么
Uh... Sure.
好的
I was very impressed with
我对你成功突破我的安保系统
how you managed to get past my security system.
印象深刻
Freezing that metal was particularly clever.
冰冻金属门那一招很聪明
Were you watching me?
你在监视我
Scott, I've been watching you for a while.
斯科特 我已经监视你好一段时间了
Ever since you robbed Vista Corp.
从你抢劫维斯塔公司开始
Oh! Excuse me.
哦 抱歉
"Burgled" Vista Corp.
应该说偷
Vista's security system was one of the most advanced in the business.
维斯塔的安保系统是业界
It was supposed to be unbeatable.
本应固若金汤
But you beat it.
但还是被你成功突破了
Would you like some sugar?
要加点糖吗
Yeah, thanks.
好的 谢谢
You know what? I'm okay.
还是不要了
How do you make them do that?
你是怎么让它们做到的
Ants can lift objects 50 times their weight.
蚂蚁可以举起它们体重五十倍的东西
They build, farm, they cooperate with each other.
它们筑巢 翻土 它们之间相互配合
Right. But how do you make them do that?
我知道 但你怎么让它们做到的
I use electromagnetic waves to stimulate their olfactory nerve center.
我用电磁波刺激它们的嗅觉神经中枢
I speak to them.
和它们讲话
I can go anywhere, hear anything,
我无所不在
and see everything.
眼观六路 耳听八方
And still know absolutely nothing.
但仍然一无所知
I'm late to meet Cross.
我见克罗斯要迟到了
Uh... Dr. Pym?
呃… 皮姆博士
You don't need to raise your hand, Scott.
你不用举手的 斯科特
Sorry, I just have one question.
抱歉 我有个问题
Who are you, who is she, what the hell's going on,
你是谁 她又是谁 这到底什么情况
and can I go back to jail now?
还有我现在可以回去坐牢了吗
Come with me.
跟我来
40 years ago, I created a formula that altered atomic relative distance.
四十年前 我发明了一个公式
Huh?
什么
I learned how to change the distance between atoms.
我在研究如何改变原子之间的距离
That's what powers the suit.
也是这套战衣的威力所在
That's why it works.
这就是它工作的原理
Wow.
哇
- Whoa! -But it was dangerous.
-哇 -但是它很危险
It was too dangerous.
非常危险
So I hid it from the world.
所以我只能将它隐匿于世
And that's when I switched gears and I started my own company.
后来我转而开办了自己的公司
Pym Tech.
皮姆科技
I took on a young protégé called Darren Cross.
我收了一个年轻学生叫达伦·克罗斯
Darren Cross.
达伦·克罗斯
He's a big deal.
他可是个风云人物
But before he was a big deal, he was my assistant.
在他成为风云人物之前 还只是我的助手
I thought I saw something in him. The son I never had, perhaps.
我在他身上看到一些特质 我从没见过这样的孩子
He was brilliant, but as we became close,
他很聪明 但随着我们越来越亲近
he began to suspect that I wasn't telling him everything.
他开始怀疑我对他有所隐瞒
He heard rumors about what was called the Pym Particle,
他听到有关皮姆粒子的传言
and he became obsessed with recreating my formula.
于是他沉迷于想复制我的公式
But I wouldn't help him.
但是我不愿意帮他
How could he do that?
他怎么做到的
The board's chairman is my daughter, Hope.
董事会主席是我的女儿 霍普
She was the deciding vote.
她投了决定票
But she came back to me
但是当她看到克罗斯就要破解我的公式时
when she saw how close Cross was to cracking my formula.
她又回到我身边
The process is highly volatile.
他的研究过程很不稳定
If one isn't protected by a specialized helmet,
如果没有专业头盔的保护
it can affect the brain's chemistry.
将会影响大脑化学反应
I don't think Darren realizes this,
我觉得达伦还没意识到这一点
and, you know, he's not the most stable guy to begin with.
你知道 他原本就不是个稳重的人
So, what do you want from me?
所以 你们想要我干什么
Scott, I believe that everyone deserves a shot at redemption.
斯科特 我相信每个人都应有自我救赎的机会
Do you?
你信吗
I do.
是的 我信
If you can help me,
如果你可以帮我
I promise I can help you be with your daughter again.
我保证 我可以让你和女儿重新团聚
Now, are you ready to redeem yourself?
现在 你准备好自我救赎了吗
Absolutely.
当然
My days of breaking into places and stealing shit are done.
我私闯民宅偷东西的日子 已经一去不复返了
What do you want me to do?
需要我做什么
I want you to break into a place and steal some shit.
我想让你私闯民宅偷东西
Are you gonna be home for dinner tonight?
你今天晚上回家吃饭吗
Uh, yeah. I'll pick something up. Text me.
是的 我有点事 短信联系
Okay. Good news?
好的 是好消息吗
Uh... I don't know. It's news.
呃… 我也不知道 只是个消息
Are you trying to find my daddy?
你在找我爸爸吗
Yeah, I am, sweetheart.
是 是的 小甜心
I just want your daddy to be safe.
我只是想你爸爸安然无恙
Hope you don't catch him.
但愿你抓不到他
This isn't the first time these guys
这些人已经不是第一次
have tried to get their hands on game-changing weaponry.
想要控制改变世界格局的新型武器了
That's Mitchell Carson, Ex-Head of Defense at S.H.I.E.L.D.
这是米切尔·卡森 神盾局前防卫部部长
Presently in the business of toppling governments.
现在正致力于四处推翻政权
He always wanted my tech.
他一直觊觎我的技术
And now, unless we break in and steal the Yellowjacket
现在 除非我们溜进去偷出黄蜂战衣
and destroy all the data,
摧毁所有的数据
Darren Cross is gonna unleash chaos upon the world.
否则达伦·克罗斯会在全世界引发混乱
I think our first move should be calling the Avengers.
我觉得 我们首先应该通知复仇者联盟
I spent half my life
我花费大半生精力
trying to keep this technology out of the hands of a Stark.
不让这项技术落入斯塔克之手
I'm sure as hell not gonna hand-deliver it to one now.
我现在当然更不会把这项技术拱手让人
This is not some cute technology like the Iron Man suit.
这可不是钢铁侠盔甲那种花哨的技术
This could change the texture of reality.
这是可以改变现实结构的技术
Besides, they're probably too busy dropping cities out of the sky.
况且 他们可能正忙着
Okay, then why don't you just send the ants?
好吧 那你为什么不直接派你的蚂蚁去
Scott, they are ants.
斯科特 它们只是蚂蚁
Ants, they can do a lot of things, but they still need a leader.
蚂蚁虽然可以做很多事情 但它们需要一个领导者
Somebody that could infiltrate a place that's designed to prevent infiltration.
一个可以
Hank, I'm a thief, all right? I mean, I'm a good thief, but this is insane.
汉克 我只是一个小偷 好吗 我是说
He's right, Hank. And you know it.
他说的没错 汉克 我想你也明白
You've seen the footage, you know what Cross is capable of.
你已经看了录像 知道克罗斯的神通本事了
and now we have days.
而现在我们只剩几天了
I'm wearing the suit.
我来穿这套战衣
Absolutely not!
绝对不行
I know the facility inside and out. I know how Cross thinks.
我知道里面所有机关 我也知道克罗斯的想法
I know this mission better than anybody here.
我比任何人都了解这项任务
We need you close to Cross. Otherwise, this mission cannot work.
我们需要你紧跟在克罗斯身边 否则任务没法完成
- We don't have time to screw around! -Hope, please listen to me...
-我们没有时间瞎折腾了 -霍普 认真听我说…
He is a criminal! I'm your daughter.
他是一个罪犯 我可是你女儿
--No!
不行
She's right, Hank.
她说得对 汉克
I'm not your guy.
我不是最佳人选
- Why don't you wear the suit?
你为什么不穿这套战服呢
You think I don't want to?
你以为我不想吗
I can't.
是我不能穿
I spent years wearing it,
我穿了好几年
and it took a toll on me.
它对我的身体产生了副作用
You're our only option.
你是我们唯一的希望
Before Hope lost her mother,
在霍普失去母亲之前
she used to look at me like I was the greatest man in the world.
她看我就像 我是全世界最了不起的人
And now she looks at me and there's just disappointment.
现在她看着我眼神只剩下失望
It's too late for me,
对我来说太迟了
but not for you.
但你不一样
This is your chance.
这是你的机会
The chance to earn that look in your daughter's eyes.
能赢得你女儿崇拜目光的机会
To become the hero that she already thinks you are.
成为她心目中的英雄
It's not about saving our world.
这不是在拯救我们的世界
It's about saving theirs.
而是她们的
Damn. That was a good speech.
该死 真是好一通说教
Scott,
斯科特
I need you to be the Ant-Man.
我需要你成为蚁人
In the right hands,
最佳状态是
the relationship between man and suit is symbiotic.
人与衣服合二为一
The suit has power. The man harnesses that power.
战服拥有力量 人驾驭这种力量
You need to be skillful, agile, and above all,
你需要熟练使用 快速敏捷 最重要的是
you need to be fast.
一定要快
You should be able to shrink and grow
你需要瞬间
on a dime.
缩小和变大
So your size always suits your needs.
根据需求缩放自如
Now dive through the keyhole, Scott.
现在 穿过这个钥匙孔 斯科特
You charge big, you dive small, then you emerge big.
正常体型加速 穿越时要变小 穿过后再变大
Useless.
真是没用
so you have the force of a 200-pound man
所以百分之一寸大小的拳头
behind a fist a 100th of an inch wide. You're like a bullet.
约含有九十公斤的人的力量 你就像一颗子弹
I was in prison for three years. I know how to punch.
我在监狱待了三年 我知道怎么出拳
Show me.
让我瞧瞧
- Terrible. -You wanna show me how to punch?
-真差劲 -你想教我怎么出拳
Show me...
让我瞧瞧…
That's how you punch.
这才叫出拳
- She's been looking forward to this. -No kidding.
她等这一刻很久了
Hope trained in martial arts at a difficult time.
霍普在一段困难时期练过武术
Oh, by "difficult time," he means when my mother died.
噢 所谓困难时期就是我母亲去世的时候
We lost her in a plane crash.
她死于空难
It's bad enough you won't tell me how she died.
你不肯告诉我她怎么死的就算了
Could you please stop telling me that lie?
能不能别再跟我撒谎
We're working, here.
我们在训练呢
All right, princess. Let's get back to work.
好的 小公主 我们继续
Were you going for the hand?
那是你的手吗
You know, I think this regulator is holding me back.
我觉得这个调节器有点碍事
Do not screw with the regulator.
不要动调节器
If that regulator is compromised,
如果调节器被破坏
you would go subatomic.
你会变成亚原子
What does that mean?
什么意思
It means that you would enter a quantum realm.
意味着你会进入量子域
What does that mean?
这又是什么意思
It means that you would enter a reality where all concepts of time and space
意味着你会永久缩小
become irrelevant
都没有概念
as you shrink for all eternity.
的现实世界
Everything that you know
你所知的和爱的
andlove,
所有东西
gone forever.
将会永远消失
Cool. Yeah, if it ain't broke...
酷 如果它没坏就算了…
You've learned about the suit,
你已经了解了战服
but you've yet to learn about your greatest allies,
但你还需要了解你了不起的盟友
the ants.
蚂蚁
Loyal, brave,
忠诚 勇敢
and your partners on this job.
你这次任务的搭档
Paratrechina longicornis. Commonly known as crazy ants.
长角立毛蚁 通常被称为狂蚁
They're lightning fast and can conduct electricity,
它们具有闪电般的速度并且能导电
which makes them useful to fry out enemy electronics.
可用于攻击敌人的电子系统
You're not so crazy.
你没那么疯狂嘛
You're cute.
你真可爱
That was a lot scarier a second ago.
一秒钟前太可怕了
it looks like the Futures Lab has its own isolated power supply.
看起来未来实验室有一套独立的供电系统
There's a security guard posted around the clock.
而且全天候都有警卫执勤
We'll need you to take him out to deactivate the security systems.
我们需要你打晕他 然后解除安保系统
Okay, who's next?
好的 接下来是谁
Paraponera clavata.
帕拉珀尼拉克拉瓦塔
I know. Bullet ants, right?
我知道 子弹蚁 对吧
Number 1 on the Schmidt pain index?
在施密特刺痛指数中位列第一
Hey, guys. Remember me from the bedroom?
嘿 伙计们 还记得我吗 卧室里见过
The Yellowjacket pod is hermetically sealed,
黄色战衣被密封在保险库里
and the only access point is a tube
接近它的唯一途径是一根管子
we estimate to be about 5 millimeters in diameter.
我们估计它的直径大约是五毫米
Why do I have a sick feeling in my stomach?
为什么我感觉胃里一直犯恶心
The tube is protected by a laser grid,
管子被激光网保护
and we can only power that down for 15 seconds.
而且我们只能断电十五秒
You're gonna need to signal the crazy ants to blow the servers,
你需要在备用电源恢复前指挥
retrieve the suit, and exit the vaults before the backup power comes on.
狂蚁破坏服务器 拿到战服
Camponotus pennsylvanicus.
宾夕法尼亚弓背蚁
Alternatively known as a carpenter ant.
俗称木工蚁
Ideal for ground and air transport.
适合于地面和航空运输
Wait a minute, I know this guy.
等等 我认识它
I'm gonna call him "Ant-thony."
我打算叫它安东蚁
That's good. That's very good.
很好 非常好
Because this time, you're really gonna have to learn how to control him.
因为这次 你真要好好学学
Tell them to put the sugar in the teacup.
让它们把糖放进茶杯中
AW! You okay? Did I hurt...
哦 你还好吗 我伤到…
Hank wants you outside for target practice.
汉克让你到外面进行针对训练
The suit has no weapons, so I made you these discs.
战服没有武器 所以我给你做了这些飞镖
Red shrinks.
红色用来缩小
Blue enlarges.
蓝色用来放大
Solenopsis mandibularis.
火蚁属
Known for their bite,
以它的叮咬闻名
They are handy to get you in and out of difficult places.
能辅助你进出各种困难的地方
You can do it, Scott. Come on.
你能做到的 斯科特 加油
They're not listening to me.
它们不听我的
You have to commit. You have to mean it.
你必须投入 精准传达你的意思
No shortcuts, no lies.
没有捷径 不能欺骗
Throwing insults into the mix will not do anyone any good, Hope.
说话带刺
We don't have time for coddling.
我们没有时间宠着他
Our focus should be on helping Scott!
我们的焦点应该是帮助斯科特
Really?
是吗
Is that where our focus should be?
这是我们应该聚焦的吗
H0pe!
霍普
I don't know why I came to you in the first place.
我不懂为什么一开始会来找你
We can't do this without her.
我们不能没有她
You gotta lock your doors.
你应该把车门锁上
I mean, really, there's some weird folks in this neighborhood.
我是说 真的 这附近有很多奇怪的人
Do you think this is a joke?
你以为这是闹着玩吗
Do you have any idea what he's asking you to risk?
你有没有想过 他让你冒多大的险
You have a daughter.
你有一个女儿
I'm doing this for her.
我做这些就是为了她
You know, when my mother died, I didn't see him for two weeks.
你知道吗 当我妈妈过世时 我两周都没有见到他
He was in grief.
他在悲痛之中
Yeah, so was I, and I was seven.
是 我也是 我当时只有七岁
And he never came back. Not in any way that counted.
他从没回来过 从没真正回来过
He just sent me off to boarding school.
他只是把我送去了寄宿学校
You know, I thought,
我以为
with all that's at stake,
在这种危机关头
just maybe we might have a chance of making peace.
也许我们能有机会重归于好
But, even now, he still wants to shut me out.
但即便是现在 他内心还是在排斥我
He doesn't wanna shut you out. He trusts you.
他没有排斥你 他信任你
Then why are you here?
那他为什么会找你来
It proves that he loves you.
这证明他爱你
Hope. Look at me.
霍普 看着我
I'm expendable.
我可以是牺牲品
That's why I'm here.
这就是我来这里的原因
You must have realized that by now.
你现在应该明白
I mean, it's why I'm in the suit and you're not.
是我穿着战服 而不是你穿
He would rather lose this fight than lose you.
他宁愿输了这场战斗也不愿失去你
AnyWaY- --
真的…
You know, I didn't know you had a daughter
你知道吗 我当时报警的时候
when I called the cops on you.
我真不知道你有个女儿
What's her name?
她叫什么名字
Cassie.
凯茜
It's a pretty name.
好美的名字
That's how it works.
这样才行
Think about Cassie.
想着凯茜
About how badly you want to see her. And use that to focus.
想着你有多想见她 利用这个来集中注意力
Open your eyes
睁开眼睛
and just think about what you want the ants to do.
专心思考你想让蚂蚁们做什么
That's good!
很好
Your mother convinced me
你妈妈当时说服了我
to let her join me on my missions.
让她加入了我的任务
They called her the Wasp.
他们叫她黄蜂女
She was born to it.
她对这个很有天分
And there's not a day that goes by
我没有一天不在后悔
that I don't regret having said yes.
我后悔当初答应了她
It was 1987.
那是一九八七年
Separatists had hijacked a Soviet missile silo in Kursk
分裂主义者劫持了苏联位于库尔斯克的导弹发射井
and launched an ICBM at the United States.
向美国发射了一枚洲际弹道导弹
The only way to the internal mechanics
唯一能进入导弹内部结构的方法
was through solid titanium.
是穿过钛固体
I knew I had to shrink between the molecules to disarm the missile.
我知道我必须缩小到分子状态穿进去 才能拆除导弹
But my regulator had sustained too much damage.
但我的调节器已经遭受了太多损坏
Your mother,
你的母亲
she didn't hesitate.
她没有犹豫
Janet! No!
珍妮特 不要
She turned off her regulator
她关掉了她的调节器
and went subatomic
变成了亚原子
to deactivate the bomb.
去拆除导弹
And she was gone.
然后她就走了
Your mom died a hero.
你的妈妈死得很英勇
And I spent the next 10 years
那以后的十年间我一直
trying to learn all I could about the quantum realm.
尽我所能的去研究量子领域
You were trying to bring her back.
你是想带她回来
But all I learned was we know nothing.
但我研究到 我们对此还是一无所知
It's not your fault.
这不是你的错
She made her choice.
她自己做的决定
But why didn't you tell me that sooner?
但你为什么没早点告诉我
I was trying to protect you.
我是想保护你
I lost your mother.
我已经失去了你的母亲
I didn't mean to lose you, too.
我不想再失去你
This is awesome.
太棒了
It's awesome, you know?
这太棒了
You guys are breaking down walls, you're healing.
你们俩在解除心防 伤口在愈合
It's important.
这很重要
I ruined the moment, didn't I?
我破坏了气氛 对吗
Yes, you did. Yes.
是的 是的
I'm going to make some tea.
我去泡杯茶
Nailed it!
搞定
That's a good boy, Ant-them.
好孩子 安东蚁
The final phase of your training will be a stealth incursion.
训练的最后一阶段是秘密入侵
It's freezing!
冻死了
You couldn't make a suit with a flannel lining?
你就不能做一件法兰绒的战服吗
You must retrieve this prototype of a signal decoy.
你必须取回这个信号伪装的原型机
It's a device that I invented during my S.H.l.E.L.D. days.
这个装置是我在神盾局时发明的
We need it to counteract the transmission blockers
我们需要用它来对付克罗斯在未来实验室保险库里
that Cross installed in the Futures vault.
安装的传输阻滞器
It's currently collecting dust
它正在纽约州最北部
in one of Howard Stark's old storage facilities in upstate New York.
霍华德·斯塔克的一处旧仓库里吃灰呢
Should be a piece of cake.
拿到手应该是小菜一碟
You're over the target area.
你在目标区域上空了
Disengage now, Scott!
现在出发 斯科特
Squadron A, go!
A中队 出发
B, go!
B中队 出发
C, go!
C中队 出发
All right, Ant-thony, please don't drop me this time.
好了 安东蚁 拜托这次别又让我掉下去了
Oh, it feels like a big leap from sugar cubes to this!
感觉从运糖块到这个跨度太大啊
Stay calm.
保持冷静
Guys? We might have a problem.
各位 我们可能有麻烦了
Hank, didn't you say this was some old warehouse?
汉克 你不是说这是一个旧仓库吗
It's not!
这并不是
You son of a bitch!
你个混蛋
- Scott, get out of there. -Abort!
-斯科特 撤退 -任务中止
Abort now!
现在中止
No, it's okay. it doesn't look like anyone's home.
不 没事 看起来没人在家
Ant-them, get me to the mo“!
安东蚁 带我去楼顶
He's gonna lose the suit.
他会丢了这套战服的
He's gonna lose his life.
他会丢了性命的
All right, I'm on the roof of the target building.
好了 我在目标大楼的楼顶了
Somebody's home, Scott.
有人回家了 斯科特
MAN". What's going on down there, Sam?
下面什么情况 山姆
It's the Falcon!
是猎鹰
I had a sensor trip but I'm not seeing anything.
感应器有反应 但我没看见什么东西
Wait a second.
等一下
Abort, Scott! Abort now!
中止 斯科特 现在中止
It's okay. He can't see me.
没事 他看不见我
I can see you.
我能看见你
He can see me.
他能看见我
Hi. I'm Scott.
嗨 我是斯科特
Did he just say, "Hi, I'm Scott"?
他刚才说嗨 我是斯科特吗
- What are you doing here? -First off, I'm a big fan.
你来这里干什么
Appreciate it. So, who the hell are you?
很感激 那么 你到底是谁
I'm Ant-Man.
我是蚁人
What? You haven't heard of me?
怎么了 你没听说过我吗
No, you wouldn't have heard of me.
不 你不会听说过我的
You wanna tell me what you want?
你想告诉我你要什么吗
I was hoping I could grab a piece of technology.
我想要一件高科技装置
Just for a few days. I'm gonna return it.
借用几天 我会还回来的
I need it to save the world. You know how that is.
我需要用它拯救世界 你懂的
I know exactly how that is.
对啊 我太懂了
Located the breach.
找到闯入者了
- Bringing him in. -Sorry about this!
-正在抓他 -对不起了
What the hell are you doing?
你到底在干什么
Breach is an adult male, who has some sort of shrinking tech.
闯入者是一个成年男性
Sorry!
对不起
Look, I'm sorry about this. Sorry.
真的对不起了
That's enough!
玩够了
Ant-thony! A little help!
安东蚁 帮我一把
I've lost visual.
我看不到你了
He's inside my pack!
他在我背包里
Sorry!
对不起
You seem like a really great guy.
你好像很了不起
It's really important to me that Cap never finds out about this.
千万别让美国队长发现这事 这对我很重要
That was completely irresponsible and dangerous!
这事完全是不负责任 还很危险
You jeopardized everything!
你把所有的事都搞砸了
You got it.
你拿到了
Well done.
干得好
Wait a minute.
等等
Did you just compliment me?
你刚刚是在夸我吗
- He did, didn't he? -Kind of sounded like he did.
他在夸我 没错吧
I was good, wasn't I?
我以前也很棒 不是吗
Hey, how about the fact that I fought an Avenger and didn't die?
嘿 我单挑一个复仇者还活着回来了 怎么样
Let us not dwell on the past.
我们别沉醉于过去里了
We gotta finish our planning.
我们得完成计划
Don't mind him.
别理他
You did good.
你干得漂亮
Darren.
达伦
How the hell did you get in here?
你怎么进来的
You left the front door open, Hank.
汉克 你前门没锁
It's official.
说真的
You're old.
你老了
The plans.
计划图纸
He Will kill him.
达伦会杀了他的
Well, to what do I owe this pleasure?
大驾光临 有何指教
I have good news.
我有好消息
Really?
是吗
What's that?
什么好消息
Pym Tech, the company you created,
皮姆科技 也就是你创建的公司
is about to become one of the most profitable operations in the world.
即将成为这世界上
We're anticipating $15 billion in sales, tomorrow alone.
仅仅明天一天的销售额 预计可以达到一百五十亿
You're welcome.
不用谢我
I know this is odd, but I'd like you to be there.
我知道这有点怪 但是我希望你在现场
This is my moment. I want you to see it.
由你来见证属于我的时刻
Sure, Darren. Yeah, sure.
没问题 达伦
I'll be there.
我会去的
What did you see in me?
你在我身上看到了什么
I don't know what you mean.
我不懂你的意思
All those years ago, you picked me.
很多年前 你选择了我
What did you see?
看上我什么
I saw myself.
我自己
Then why did you push me away?
那你为什么又放弃我
Because I saw too much of myself.
因为我发现我们俩太像了
He knows. He's baiting you.
他知道了 他在给你布局
We have to call it off.
我们得取消计划
We're all taking risks.
我们得冒这个险
What if he saw me here?
如果他看见我在这怎么办
He didn't. There's no way.
不可能 他不可能看见你
- How do you know that?
你怎么知道
Darren, hi.
达伦 你好
Hope, where are you right now?
霍普 你现在在哪
I'm at home. Why?
我在家 怎么了
I just saw Hank.
我刚刚见过汉克了
I still get nothing but contempt from him.
我从他那得到的只有鄙视 其他的一无所获
Don't let him rile you up. He's just a senile old man.
犯不着为了他动肝火 他就是个糟老头
We need to start everyone working around the clock.
我们需要让所有人全天侯干活
Get the assembly line up and running.
让流水线设备投入运行
And I'm tripling security.
我还要加强三倍安保
Full sensors at all entrances
所有入口处都安装感应器
and exterior air vents fitted with steel micro-mesh.
所有外围通风口都要安装微型钢制网罩
Great. Good idea.
很好 好主意
He's tripling security. He's lost his mind, and he's onto you.
他加强了三倍安保 他疯了 他盯上你了
But he is not onto you.
但他没有盯上你
He's adding full body scanners to all entrances
他在所有入口都加装全身扫描
and closing exterior vents.
还有封锁外围通风口
How are we gonna get Scott inside?
我们怎么才能把斯科特弄进去
The water main.
总水管
You can't add security to a water main.
你不能在总水管设安保
The pressure is too strong, but if we can decrease it,
水压太大 但如果我们能减压
that's how I get in.
我就能进去
Somebody would have to reach the building's control center
这样就得有人去大楼控制中心
to change the water pressure.
调节水压
Hank and I will be beside Cross. How are we supposed to do that?
汉克和我在那个时候会在克洛斯身旁
So we expand our team.
我们得扩大我们的队伍
What do we need?
我们需要什么
A fake security guard on the inside to de-pressurize the water system,
一个人伪装成保安进入大楼内部
somebody else to hack in to the power supply
另一个黑进电源供应系统
and kill the laser grid,
关闭激光网
and a getaway guy.
还有一个人负责接应
No, no. No, no, no. Not those three Wombats. No way.
不不 不行 不要那三个草包 绝对不行
Thank you for the coffee, ma'am.
谢谢你的咖啡 女士
It's not too often that you rob a place and then get welcomed back.
这事确实少见 很少有人偷完东西 还被盛情款待的
Because we just robbed you.
毕竟我们刚来偷过东西
You know that he was arrested for stealing a smoothie machine, right?
你知道他是因为偷了一个冰沙机被抓的 是吧
Two smoothie machines.
是两个冰沙机
Are you sure they can handle this?
你确定他们能行
Oh, we can handle it. We're professionals.
我们能搞定 我们很专业
You'll forgive us if we're not instilled with confidence.
原谅我们对你们实在没有什么信心
Well, hey, everybodyjust kick back and relax a little bit, man.
嘿 伙计 大家都应该静下心来放松点
We know our business.
我们的业务能力很高超
We broke into this spooky-ass house, didn't we?
这么坚固的鬼房子我们都钻进来了 你说是不是
Iletyou.
我放你进来的
Well, one could say that I let you let me.
我还说 是我让你放我进来呢
- Look, it's okay. They can handle this. -Yeah, we can handle it.
没问题 他们能搞定
- You got their credentials? - He's in the system.
-你能给他证件吗 -他在公司系统里了
- I'm in the system? -You're in the system.
我在系统里
The system?
系统
Yeah, we're doomed.
我们死定了
All right.
好了
There's something you guys need to see.
你们得看看这个
When you get to this corner,
你到了这个转角
there's gonna be three offices on your left side.
你的左边会有三间办公室
Damn!
我靠
Whoa! That's so cool, bro!
哇喔 真是酷毙了 兄弟
Now, look, this is gonna get weird, all right?
听着 接下来可能有点诡异
It's pretty freaky, but it's safe. There's no reason to be scared.
怪吓人的 不过没危险
Oh, no, no. Daddy don't get scared.
哦 不不 老子才不怕
- Really? -Yeah.
-是吗 -当然
Good.
很好
This is the work of gypsies.
这是吉普赛人的鬼把戏
That's witchcraft.
那是巫术
Wow, that's amazing.
哇 真神奇
That's like some David Copperfield shit.
就像大卫·科波菲尔的魔术
That's some kind of wizardry.
像是魔法
This is sorcery!
是巫术
How'd you do that, bro?
你怎么做到的 兄弟
Don't freak out. Look at your shoulder.
别吓着了 看看你肩膀
Ahhh!
啊啊啊
Get off! Get off!
下去 下去
Wait, I thought Daddy didn't get scared!
我以为你不害怕呢
I gave them each half a Xanax
我给他们每人吃了半片镇定药
and Hank explained the science of the suit to them.
汉克给他们解释了战服的原理
They fell right asleep.
他们马上睡着了
Hey, look, I wanna thank you for...
嘿 听着 我想谢谢你
No, please don't.
别谢了
We're all doing this for reasons much bigger than any one of us.
我们做这事不为别的
I'm just glad that you might have a slight chance of maybe pulling this off.
我很开心你还有那么
Hey, thank you, you know, for that pep talk.
嘿 谢谢你鼓励我
You know, the honest truth is, I actually went from despising you
说真的 我从最开始鄙视你
to almost liking you.
到现在都快喜欢上你了
You really should write poetry.
你真的应该去写诗歌
Get some sleep, Scott.
去睡吧 斯科特
All right, just so we're clear, everyone here knows their role, right?
好了 都清楚了吧
- Dave? -Wheels on the ground.
-戴夫 -我是开车的
- Kurt? -Eyes in the sky.
-库尔特 -我负责监视
- Luis? -Oh, man, you know it.
-路易斯 -噢 伙计 你懂的
You know what? I get to wear a uniform.
知道吗 我爱死穿制服了
- That's what's up. -Luis.
-那就是我要做的 -路易斯
I'm sorry. I'm good. I'm good. I'm just excited.
对不起 我没问题 我只是有点小兴奋
Plus, your girlfriend's really hot.
再说 你女朋友那么火辣
So, you know, that makes me nervous, too.
你知道 搞得我有点紧张
And you are very beautiful, ma'am.
女士 你真美
- Oh, my Lord. -She's not my...
-噢 天啊 -她不是我的
Like a whistling. You know what I'm saying? To like, blend in.
可以吹口哨 明白我的意思么 混进去
No. Don't whistle. No whistling.
不行 不许吹口哨
It's not The Andy Griffith Show. No whistling.
这不是安迪·格里菲斯秀 不许吹口哨
All clear in Sector One.
一区一切正常
Step out.
出来
All clear.
一切正常
We're set.
我们就位了
Wish me luck.
祝我好运
Utilities online.
设备已连接
Hey! What are you doing?
嘿 你在干嘛
Uh... Boss-man said to secure the area, so I'm securing it.
老大让我巡视这区 所以我正在巡视
I'm the boss.
我就是老大
- Oh. -Utilities 1.3...
-喔 -设备1.3
Water level is dropping!
水压正在下降
Coming up on extraction pipe.
从抽气管爬上去
All right, I see it.
看到了
All right, come on, I gotta get up there. That's it. That's it, guys! Yes!
来吧 加油 我要上去
Yes! You got it! You got it! Come on!
你们可以的 你们可以做到 加油
- All right, let's fly, Ant-thony.
好了 安东蚁 飞起来
The Ant-Man is in the building.
蚁人已经在楼里了
Pym's pulling up. Right on time.
皮姆在停车 时间刚刚好
Got a Crown Vic right outside there.
那里停了一辆维多利亚皇冠
Considering the Crown Vic's the most commonly used car
维多利亚皇冠是最常见的
for undercover cops, man,
便衣警车 伙计
yes, this is problem.
这个就是问题
That's Pym.
那是皮姆
Oh, no.
哦不
I'm deploying the bullet ants.
我在部署子弹蚁
Papanera Claire de Merna Merna...
名字叫帕拉巴拉拉什么的
I don't remember what it's called, but I feel bad for this guy.
我不记得叫什么了 不过那家伙要有好戏看了
- What's up, man? -Hey.
-你好 伙计 -嘿
Ow! Ow!
啊 啊
See? That's what I'm talking about.
看见没 这正是我想说的
That's what I call an unfortunate casualty
我管它叫 执行重要任务
in a very serious operation.
遇到不幸事故
Signal decoy in place.
信号干扰器就位
Mean, pretty lady did good, Scott.
也就是说漂亮小姐成功了 斯科特
Looks like Pym's getting arrested.
看样子他们要逮捕皮姆了
Scott, we have problem.
斯科特 我们有麻烦了
Problem? What's the problem?
麻烦 什么麻烦
Dave! Dave, that's not part of plan!
戴夫 戴夫 计划里可不是这样的
Listen to me.
听我说
If I don't get into this building, people will die.
如果我不进去 里面的人会死的
That's awfully dramatic.
真是够戏剧的台词啊
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑
Problem solved.
麻烦解决了
Well...
喔
How do I look?
我看上去怎么样
There he is.
他来了
Just in time. Come on.
真准时 来吧
12-point verification.
视网膜12点验证
Little over-the-top, don't you think, Darren?
防范做得太过了 不觉得吗 达伦
Confirming authorization level.
-确认授权级别 -安保永远都不嫌多
Access granted.
允许进入
Gotta hand it to you, Darren.
不得不佩服你 达伦
You really did it.
你真的做到了
And you only know the half of it, Hank.
你只知其一不知其二 汉克
Arriving in second position.
正在前往第二个目标
All right, top speed, Ant-thony. Let's go!
极速前进 安东蚁 我们上
Proceeding to command position.
继续向目的地前进
I'll be right back, Ant-thony.
我去去就回 安东蚁
All right, guys. I'm in position.
好了伙计们 我已就位
I'm gonna signal the ants.
我马上就给蚂蚁们发指令了
No, no, no, no, no!
不不不 不
Did you see that?
你看到了吗
Assume formation.
列队
All right, you cute little crazies,
来吧 你们这些可爱的小疯子
let's fry these servers!
烧毁服务器吧
Let's go get 'em, buddy!
我们上 伙计
Servers are fried.
服务器烧毁了
Data backup completely erased.
数据备份也彻底被抹掉了
Heading to the particle chamber.
正在赶往粒子室
Hello, Dr. Cross.
你好 克罗斯博士
My associates have agreed to your terms.
我的合伙人已经同意你的条款了
Wonderful.
好极了
Mr. Carson introduced me to these fine gentlemen here.
卡森先生把我介绍给了这几位先生
They're representatives of Hydra.
他们是九头蛇的代表
They're not what they were.
他们已经改头换面了
They're doing some interesting work.
他们现在做些很有趣的工作
And I'm enjoying myself.
而我也很享受这种乐趣
You tried to hide your technology from me.
你一直试图向我隐瞒你的研究成果
And now it's gonna blow up in your face.
可现在它即将在你面前大放异彩
Wow! I mean, I saw that punch coming a mile away,
哇哦 我早就猜到你会打我
but I just figured it'd be all pathetic and weak.
但我还以为会是软绵绵的一拳
Well, you figured wrong.
那你就猜错了
I know this van.
我认得这辆车
ATWbOdy home?
有人吗
All right, guys. I'm here.
好了伙计们 我到了
I'm setting the charges.
正在安装炸弹
Great job, guys. I'll take it from here.
干得漂亮 伙计们 接下来就交给我吧
Good boy, Ant-them.
好样的 安东蚁
Final position.
到达最终目的地了
Guys, how we looking on that laser grid?
伙计们 你们还没有搞定激光网吗
- Almost. - No, you're not.
-就快了 -你还差得远呢
- I'm getting close! -No, you're not.
-马上就好了 -才没有
San Francisco P.D.!
旧金山警察局
Out of the van!
快从车子里出来
I know you're in there!
我知道你们就在里面
- Make it go faster. -Dude, seriously.
再快点
Ready to jump. Do you read, Kurt?
准备跳了 你那边弄好了吗 库尔特
So close.
就快好了
- Okay, hold up! Wait a minute! -Freeze!
-举起手来 -等等 -别动
There was a black guy that looked exactly like me
刚刚有一个和我长得很像的黑人袭击了我们
who attacked us and put us in the back of this disgusting van.
然后他把我们塞进了这辆令人作呕的车里
- Get out of the van! - Okay, I'm coming.
-给我出来 -好好 我这就出来
Take it easy!
你慢点啊
No, I will not move! Go now!
不 我现在还不能离开 快跳
- Wait! -What? What do you mean, "Wait"?
等等
What? What?
什么 怎么了
Hey, little guy.
你好呀 小家伙
I always suspected you had a suit stored away somewhere.
我一直怀疑你在某个地方藏了一套战服
Which begs the question,
那问题就来了
who is the new Ant-Man?
谁是那个新的蚁人
Who is the man that my beloved mentor
谁是那个比我更受
trusted even more than me?
我敬爱导师信任的人
Scott Lang.
斯科特·朗
A martyr
一个勇士
who took on the system and paid the price,
一个因为攻破公司的系统而失去了家庭
losing his family and his only daughter in the process.
失去了女儿并拥有献身精神的人
Exactly your kind of guy, Hank!
这正是你的最佳人选 汉克
He escapes his jail cell without leaving any clue as to how.
他逃出了拘留所 没有留下任何线索
despite having no money to his name.
尽管他名下穷得一分钱都没有
And now he brings me the Ant-Man suit.
可现在 他却给我带来了蚁人战服
The only thing that can rival my creation.
也只有这件东西能与我的发明抗衡
Darren, don't do this.
达伦 别这样
If you sell to these men,
如果你把它卖给了这些人
it's gonna be chaos.
将会掀起一场腥风血雨
I already have.
我已经卖了
And for twice the price,
还是以两倍的价格
thanks to you.
这得感谢你
It's not easy to successfully infiltrate an Avengers facility.
要潜进复仇者联盟的基地可不是件容易的事
Thankfully, word travels fast.
幸运的是 消息传播得很快
I'll sell them the Yellowjacket, but I'm keeping the particle to myself.
我会把黄蜂战衣卖给他们
They don't run on diesel.
战衣不是靠柴油的
If you want the fuel, you'll have to come to me.
想要补充能源 你还是得来找我
What do you call the only man
你会怎么称呼那个
who can arm the most powerful weapon in the world?
世界上拥有最厉害的武器的人
The most powerful man in the world.
世界的统治者
You proud of me yet?
现在你为我感到骄傲了吗
You can stop this, Darren. It's not too late.
达伦 现在停手还为时不晚
It's been too late for a long time now.
无法挽回了 这已成定局
Darren!
达伦
What are you doing?
你在做什么
He wasn't any more capable of caring for you than he was for me.
他对你还没我对你好
This is not who you are.
这不是真正的你
It's the particles altering your brain chemistry.
那些粒子改变了你的头脑
Wait! Wait, wait, wait, wait.
等等 等等 等一下
You're right. I have to be the one to do it.
你是对的 我应该亲自动手
Here we go.
开始了
Drop your gun.
放下你的枪
You know, I came to the house the other night to kill him,
那天晚上我去他家里 本来是要杀了他
but you were there.
但你在那里
You're sick and I can help you. Just put the gun down.
你失去理智了 我可以帮你 把枪放下
I wasn't ready to kill you then,
我那时并不想杀你的
but I think I am now!
但现在我愿意了
Drop your gun now!
快把枪放下
You picked the wrong side, Hope.
你站错了队伍了 霍普
43am
爸爸
Hank, no.
汉克 不
Hank? Listen, you're gonna be okay.
汉克 听着 你会没事的
- All right? You're gonna be just fine.
你会好起来的
Take the suit off, or I'll blow your brains out and peel it off.
把战服脱下来 不然我就一枪打爆你的头 再扒了它
We got a 10-33 at Pym Tech.
突发事件 我们在皮姆科技公司
Request immediate backup!
请求立即增援
Go, go, 90!
快走
Get me to the roof.
送我到楼顶
And radio ahead.
把消息传下去
I want to make sure the helicopter is ready to take off.
我要确保直升机能随时起飞
kill anything that comes out of that vault!
从那库房里出来的 格杀勿论
Dad, can you move?
爸爸 你还能动吗
We need to get him out of here.
我们得把他从这里弄出去
Go get that suit.
快 快去拿那套战衣
Hey, Scotty.
嘿 斯科特
Hey, did I save your life?
嘿 我有救到你的命了吗
Thank you, Luis.
谢谢你 路易斯
- Are we the good guys? -Yeah.
-我们是好人 对吧 -是的
- We're the good guys, right? -Yeah, we're the good guys.
我们真的是好人 对吗
Feels kinda weird, you know.
这感觉有点奇怪
Yeah, but we're not done yet.
嗯 但我们还有任务没做完
Get out of here before this place blows!
在这栋楼爆炸之前撤出去
Damn it! That guy.
见鬼 还有那家伙
Hey! We're getting out of here!
嘿 我们得离开这
The charges are set.
炸弹已经设定好了
We've gotta find a way out of here. And fast.
我们得尽快找到出去的方法
Don't worry.
别担心
I'm not gonna die.
我死不了
And neither are you.
你也是
It's not a keychain.
这可不仅仅是一个钥匙扣
It's total chaos in here! Multiple shots fired!
现场一片混乱 还有多次枪击
And there's a tank.
还多了一辆坦克
A little help!
帮帮忙
I got it.
我来吧
We need a doctor!
我们需要医生
We've got him.
我们接到他了
Let's go)!
快走
Ant-thony!
安东蚁
Go!
走
You're gonna regret that.
你会后悔的
Wait a minute! Get out of that van!
等一下 从那车里出来
- What? -Get out of that van!
-什么 -快从那车里出来
It's too loud, there's a tank. I can't hear you!
这里太吵了 还有辆坦克 我听不见你说什么
Are you crazy? Put the gun down!
你疯了吗 放下枪
The windows!
窗户坏了
Did you think you could stop the future with a heist?
你真以为抢走了战衣就能阻止未来吗
it was neverjust a heist!
我做的可不止抢战衣
Put the gun down!
把枪放下
Okay, I got him, I got him. There he is! Go, go, go!
好 我看到他了 就在那 快 快
We gotta set her down somewhere.
我们得找个地方降落
I'm gonna disintegrate you!
我要让你粉身碎骨
Playing Disintegration by the Cure.
正在播放治疗乐队的粉身碎骨
Call 911!
快报警
- It's okay.
没事了
Freeze! Put your hands up! Get them up!
别动 举起手来
Scott?
斯科特
Paxton, you have to listen to me!
帕克斯顿 你一定要听我解释
Paxton, turn around! Take me back!
帕克斯顿 快掉头 让我回去
I am taking you back. To prison.
我是在带你回去 回监狱去
There's something in that backyard that needs to be destroyed.
那后院里有个东西必须要销毁
In the bug zapper. There...
在灭蚊灯里 有…
You need to desist right now! Your delusions are out of hand.
你别再胡说八道了 你的幻想太离谱了
All units, we have a 2-36 in progress at 840 Winter Street.
各小组注意
- Cassie! -That's my house.
-凯茜 -那是我的家
Don't be scared.
别害怕
Paxton, let me help!
帕克斯顿 让我帮忙
- Don't move. -Let me help!
呆在这别动
- Maggie! What's going on? -He's got Cassie!
玛姬 发生了什么
- Who's got Cassie, honey? -That thing.
-谁抓住了凯茜 亲爱的 -那个东西
- Thing? - I don't know! I don't know!
-什么东西 -我不知道 我不知道
Are you a monster?
你是怪兽吗
Do I look like a monster?
我看起来像怪兽吗
I want my daddy!
我要找我爸爸
I want your daddy, too.
我也要找你爸爸
There you are.
你总算来了
Daddy, is that you?
爸爸 是你吗
Hi, peanut.
嗨 小花生
Why don't you pick on someone your own size?
你怎么不找一个跟你一样大小的人当对手呢
Now, where did you go, little guy?
现在你跑去哪了 小家伙
There you are.
找到你了
Not just me!
不止是我哦
Damn it!
该死
Go! Go!
快 快上
Scotty needs us, you know what I'm saying?
斯科特需要我们 你懂吗
Ain't nothing gonna stop us.
没有什么能阻挡我们
Back it up.
倒车
- Back it up, slow. -Yeah.
慢慢倒车
- Back it up.
-倒车 -好
-Okay.
-倒车吧 -行
- We just back it up, okay? - That's it.
-我们只是倒个车而已 -是的
- Back it up. - That's right.
-倒吧 -对
- Backin' up? - Yep, just backin' up.
在倒吗
No, no. Just back it up.
嗯 就默默倒车吧
You insult me, Scott.
你侮辱了我 斯科特
Your very existence is insulting to me.
你的存在就是对我的侮辱
You know, it'd be much easier to hit you if you were bigger.
知道吗 如果你再大点就更容易打到你了
Yeah, I agree.
是啊 我同意
Cassie!
凯茜
I'm gonna show you just how insignificant you are.
我要让你见识一下你是多么的微不足道
Cassie! I'm coming!
凯茜 我来了
That's a messed-up looking dog.
你们家的狗长得可真任性
I'm gonna destroy
我要毁掉
- everything you love.
你所珍爱的一切
Freeze! S.F.P.D.
不准动 旧金山警局
I can't break through.
我进不去
It's titanium, you idiot!
这可是钛合金 蠢货
- Get her out of here. - Come on.
-带她离开这 -来吧
Sorry, sweetheart.
对不起 亲爱的
You have to help Daddy pay for his mistakes.
你得为你爸爸犯下的错付出代价
- You stay behind me, okay? -Okay.
-躲在我后面 好吗 -好
Stay behind me.
躲在我后面
I'm gonna have to shrink between the molecules to get in there.
我必须缩小到分子级才能进去
Get away from us!
离我们远点
Daddy, help!
爸爸 救命
I love you, Cassie.
我爱你 凯茜
Daddy, where are you?
爸爸 你在哪
You could go subatomic.
你会进入次原子域
Oh, no.
噢 不
You would enter a reality
你会进入一个时间和空间的概念
where all concepts of time and space...
都会化为虚无的领域
All concepts of time and space become irrelevant.
所有时间和空间的意义都将成为泡影
...all concepts of time and space
…所有时间和空间都将成为泡影
Come back, Daddy!
爸爸 快回来
...as you shrink for all eternity.
…你将永远都在缩小
Everything that you know
你所了解的
and love,
和所珍爱的一切
gone forever.
都会化为乌有
Daddy, where are you?
爸爸 你在哪
Where are you?
你在哪
- Daddy! - Cassie.
-爸爸 -凯茜
Come back, Daddy!
快回来 爸爸
Do not screw with the regulator!
不要乱动调节器
Daddy!
爸爸
I love you so much.
我好爱你
I love you, too.
我也爱你
You know, there's a big hole in the roof.
知道吗 屋顶开了个个大洞
Sorry.
很抱歉
- Is she all right? - Yeah, she's fine.
-她还好吗 -嗯 她没事
Mommy!
妈妈
She's fine, she's fine.
她没事 她没事
HANK". Scott, please.
斯科特 拜托
You don't remember anything?
你什么都不记得了吗
Hank. I don't.
汉克 我真不记得了
There must be something else.
总得有点什么吧
Well, I suppose the human mind
我猜可能以人类的思维
just can't comprehend the experience,
目前还无法理解这样的体验
but you made it.
但你做到了
You went in,
你进去了
and you got out.
然后活着出来了
It's amazing.
简直不可思议
Scott,
斯科特
I'll walk you out.
我送你出去
Get some rest.
好好休息
Is it possible?
还有可能吗
When did this happen?
这是什么时候发生的
Nothing's happening.
并没有发生什么
Whoa. Hold on. Somethings kind of happening.
等等 还是发生了点什么的吧
Well, if that's the case,
如果真是这样的话
shoot me again.
再补我一枪吧
Yeah. I don't know what you were doing, grabbing and kissing me like that.
是啊 我都不知道你在干嘛
I'm a little surprised myself.
我自己也受到了惊吓
I have to get somewhere. I'll see you later, Hank.
我有事先走了 回见 汉克
Really, Hope.
真是的 霍普
- Scott. -Yeah?
-斯科特 -啊
- You're full of shit. -Oh, yeah.
-你就扯吧 -好吧
Scott, I met with my captain today.
斯科特 我今天跟我队长见了一面
He wanted a report on the night that you got out ofjail.
他想要你出狱那天晚上的报告
Something happened with the cameras.
监视器出了点问题
Some circuits got fried.
有些线路被烧了
But I told him that you were processed correctly.
不过我告诉他你完全是走正当程序出狱的
Really?
真的吗
PAXTONI Well, yeah.
是啊
Thank you, Paxton.
谢谢你 帕克斯顿
I'm blown away.
我很感动
Thank you for everything you do for Cassie.
谢谢你为凯茜做的一切
Well, that's my pleasure.
那是我的荣幸
But, no. This one, I did for you.
不过 这一回 我是为了你
- This is awkward. -Yeah.
-有点尴尬 -是啊
- Yeah.
是啊
- Oh, I know. -What?
-噢 我知道 -什么
- I did my first cartwheel today.
我今天翻了人生中第一个跟斗
Yeah. She has been practicing all week.
是的 她练习翻跟斗都已经一个星期了呢
But today was the magic day.
但今天终于到了见证奇迹的时刻
I recorded it on my phone. Here.
我拿手机录下来了 看
No, that can't be Cassie. That's not you.
不 这不可能是凯茜 这才不是你呢
- Yeah, it is.
-就是她 -就是我
This is a professional gymnast. There is no way that's you.
这就是个专业的体操运动员 不可能是你
Yeah, that's her.
是 真的是她
Good boy.
真乖
Sweetie, that's pretty amazing, peanut.
这真是太不可思议了 小花生
Sorry.
不好意思
It's work.
工作上的事
Yeah.
喂
All right.
好吧
Here's the deal. Just give me the facts.
这样吧 直接说 只说事实
Just the facts. Only the facts.
只要事实 不要别的
Breathe. Focus. Keep it simple.
深呼吸 集中注意力 长话短说
No, no, no. No doubt, no doubt. Okay.
好 没问题 没问题 来吧
So, I'm at this art museum with my cousin Ignacio, right?
我跟我表哥伊格纳西奥在一个艺术博物馆
And there was this, like, abstract expressionism exhibit.
那是一场抽象表现主义的展览
But you know me, I'm more like a Neo-Cubist kind of guy, right?
但是你懂我的 其实我更喜欢新立体派主义的 是吧
But there was this one Rothko that was sublime, bro! Oh, my God!
但那有一副罗斯科的画简直棒呆了 伙计 天哪
- Luis. -Okay, sorry. Sorry.
路易斯
You know, I just get excited and stuff.
你知道我一兴奋就有点话痨的
"Yo, I met this crazy-fine writer chick at the Spot last night. Like fine-fine.
我昨晚在斯波特酒吧遇见了一个
"Like crazy-stupid fine." And he goes up to the bartender and goes,
辣呀辣呀 辣得都快惹火了
"Look at the girl I'm with. You know what I'm sayin'?
瞧我泡的妞 你懂我什么意思吗
"She's crazy-stupid fine, right?"
她太他妈辣了 是吧
The bartender's all like, "Yeah, crazy-stupid fine."
然后酒保说 是啊 真他妈辣
So this writer chick tells Ignacio,
然后这个美女作家告诉伊格纳西奥
"Yo, I'm like a boss in the world of guerrilla journalism,
哟 我算得上是狗仔界的老大了
"you know what I'm saying?"
你懂我什么意思吧 伊格纳西奥说 真的吗
And she's like, "Yeah, you know what, I can't tell you who my contact is,
然后她说 是啊 你知道吧
"because he works with the Avengers."
因为他与复仇者们共事
Oh, no.
不是吧
Yeah, and this dude sounds like a badass, man.
是啊 这家伙听起来可是个狠角色 伙计
"Yo, I'm looking for this dude who's new on the scene,
我要找一个道上的新人
"who's got, like, bomb moves, right? Who you got?"
有着爆炸般行动力的人 懂了吗 你认识这种人吗
"We got a guy who swings, we got a guy who crawls up the walls.
能飞的 能爬墙的
"You gotta be more specific."
你得更具体点
So I asked Ignacio,
所以我就问伊格纳西奥
"Did the badass tell the stupid-fine writer chick
这个狠角色 是不是告诉这个超辣的美女作家
"to tell you to tell me, because I'm tight with Ant-Man,
要她让你告诉我 他在找蚁人
There's something I want to show you.
我想给你看点东西
I realized you can't destroy power.
我意识到力量是无法被毁灭的
All you can do is make sure that it's in the right hands.
我们能做的只有保证它被对的人利用
This is an advanced prototype
这是你妈和我共同研发的
that your mother and I worked on together.
升级版战衣原型
She never got to use it.
她还没来得及穿上它
But now I realize that we were... We were working on it for you.
但现在我明白了…其实这是我们为你而研发的
Maybe it's time we finished it.
也许是时候完成它了
It's about damn time.
太是时候了
FALCON". Hey, Cap!
嗨 队长
This would have been a lot easier a week ago.
这要是几周前就好办得多了
- If we call Tony... -He won't believe us.
-如果我们告诉托尼… -他不会相信我们的
Even if he did...
就算他信了
Who knows if the Accords will let him help.
天知道协议上有没有哪条规定不让他帮忙的
We're on our own.
只能靠我们自己了
Maybe not.
或许不用
I know a guy.
我认识一个家伙